競爭，每個界別都有得揀。
喺本屆立法會嘅成功實踐之上咧。
依啲係切合國家同埋香港嘅整體利益。
為議會注入新嘅力量，帶嚟新嘅氣象。
我期待參選人係展開一場高水平嘅君子之爭。
我哋都必須以實力，佢哋都必須要實力，以及正剛嘅理念，同埋服務社會嘅熱誠去決勝負。
我留意到參選人係來自唔同嘅界別，背景係多元，其中今次女性參選人嘅比例咧係突破咗兩成二嘅。
有抱負、年青有為嘅愛國愛港嘅人士，大家都懷住一顆致力為香港謀發展、為市民謀幸福嘅心。
喺依個高標準之下咧，我哋希望第八屆立法會咧係必須繼往開來，把將務實為民嘅議會工作咧係做得更好。
香港係正處於機遇同埋挑戰並存嘅關鍵時刻。第七屆立法會喺推動香港經濟同埋民生發展方面咧，交出咗亮麗嘅成績。
誒較上屆百分之十八咧係更加高，參選人咧亦都係各有優勢。我相信佢哋會將各方各面嘅經驗、新意念、新嘅政策倡議帶入新一屆嘅立法會。
部分選區嘅競爭係比上屆係更加激烈，所有嘅參選人咧都係企喺同一嘅起跑線上，冇任何人得到所謂特別嘅祝福，亦都冇穩勝嘅名單。
咁多位傳媒朋友，歡迎嚟到先。咁咧，今日咧，誒委員主席咧會就第八屆立法會選舉提名期今日結束咧，會同大家講幾句嘅。噉就為咗確保選舉公平公正啦，今日嘅記者會咧就唔涉及任何同競選活動、誒參選人或者政黨相關嘅提問嘅。噉我交畀主席先。好啊，各位傳媒界朋友。
各位市民，第八屆立法會選舉嘅提名期咧，喺今日誒下午五點鐘啱啱結束，有超過一百六十位有志之士咧係報名參選嘅。我哋見到全部參選人都係有擔當、有才幹、有。
為咗感到欣喜嘅係今次選舉啊，係延續咗第七屆立法會嘅健康現象，就係再出現九十個議席全部都係有喺競爭嘅環境下去產生嘅，每個選區都有競。
我深信會喺參選人經過選舉嘅洗禮，都會係更瞭解選民對立法會嘅期望、對社會嘅關注，將佢哋嘅聲音帶入議會，令到無論喺議會亦話政府施政咧，係更加貼地。
我呼籲選民喺十月七日。
我今日係聯同立法會秘書。
對提升特區治理嘅能力同埋效能。
説好香港嘅故事，説好中國嘅故事。
立法會係香港最重要嘅民意代表嘅機關。
立法會議員係特區管治團隊嘅重要組成部分。
踴躍投票，履行你哋嘅公民責任，選出代表你嘅代議士進入議會。
動去深入對接國家「十五五」嘅規劃，同時發揮一國兩制嚇香港嘅獨特優勢。
以身以身作則，以實際行動去展現對立法會選舉嘅支持，對香港未來嘅承擔。
支持今次立法會換屆嘅選舉，最重要係支持選舉能夠依個選舉能夠公開、公平、公正同埋安全有序咁順利舉行。
我亦都趁呢個機會咧，多謝其他唔再參選嘅議員，佢哋對立法會工作嘅投入同埋付出都係值得大家欣賞嘅。我亦都知道佢哋同我一樣會積極鼓勵更多選民去投票。
立法會選舉從來都係香港特區欠制發展嘅大事，大家唔好因為立法會已經回復理性，唔再有內耗同埋激烈嘅場面而唔重視立法會選舉同埋立法會嘅職能。
肩負重要嘅責任，新一屆嘅立法會議員係任重道遠。除咗深化行政立法良性互動，繼續為民發聲，亦都推進良政善治之外，亦要幫助香港各界把握機遇，進一步主。
今次選舉不僅係推動高質量民主發展嘅重要里程碑，亦都係全港市民選擇更好嘅未來、共創更好未來嘅關鍵時刻。我雖然唔再競逐連任，但係我會身體力行，全力。
我要相信，越多愛國愛港嘅才德兼備嘅有志之士去參選同埋加入立法會，越多選民喺立法會選舉中投票，立法會亦都會更有底氣同埋力量，説好立法會嘅故事。
誒處嘅秘書長韋碧瑤誒多華咧就發信畀全體議員、議員職員同埋秘書處所有嘅同事，呼籲大家喺十二月七日咧係踴躍投票，因為作為一個立法會一份子，依啲係責無旁貸，應該。
over。
Their commitments, capabilities and aspirations.
delivering a high quality and civil election.
The election will enable every contestant to know better.
They come from all walks of life, with diverse background and distinct strength.
香港是 now at a critical juncture, filled with opportunities and challenges.
The competition in some constituencies are fiercer than in the last election.
但 share the same devotion to Hong Kong's development and to the best interests of the people.
The public expectation on Legco and their concerns on the citizens of Hong Kong.
160 young and promising contestants. All the contestants are patriots who love Hong Kong and have shown
With their professional experiences in different sectors, I believe they will bring a new paradigm for the eighth legco.
我而家用英文講誒講一講好嘛。The nomination period for the general election of the eighth Legislative Council ends today.
The seventh legco has delivered an impressive result in promoting Hong Kong's economic development and people's livelihood.
We are delighted to see that the upcoming election remain highly competitive. Same as the previous legislative election, all ninety seats seats in each constituency are contested.
by bringing their voices into the legislature, it will make both the legal and government governance more down to earth and align with the overall interests of the country and Hong Kong.
no one would receive the so-called special spacing, as all contestants start on the same starting line and compete on the basis of their ability, policy platforms and their dedication to serve to serving the society.
啲。
in logical.
although I am not running for the election, I will fully support the upcoming.
Lesco is an important part of the Hong Kong SAR government governing team.
integrate into the national development under the fifteen-five years plan.
今日，多拉，總書記和電科書記，有。
although the legislature has returned to rationality and there's no longer internal strife.
立法會 election has always been a major event in the constitutional development of the Hong Kong SAR.
bearing important responsibilities for enhancing the capability and effectiveness of the governance.
build on this high standard, I firmly believe the eighth legco will do a better job and yield more fruitful results.
and I have issued a letter to all members and their staff, as well as all staff of the secretariat, urging them to vote.
general election, a smooth conduct of the election in an open, fair and just, safe and orderly manner, is of the paramount importance.
It is our duty to lead by example, taking concrete actions to show support for the electoral election and demonstrating our commitment to Hong Kong SAR's future. Thank you.
The upcoming election is not just only an important milestone for advancing high-quality democratic development, but also a key moment for all Hong Kong people to choose and create a better future.
Members of the eighth Legislative Council are charged with heavy responsibility for speaking on behalf of the people and promoting good governance. They also need to help all sectors of Hong Kong to seize opportunities and further.
Our work will be seems to be easier, but every vote counts in this election. I urge all voters to fulfil their civic responsibility and cast their ballots on the seventh of December to elect your representative.
就。
買到呢個貨。
再參選啦！
今屆咧，其實都。
社會一塊關心少咗。
咁第二就係即係。
誒，自從冇一個報紙後期。
嘅時候角色咁傾條衫畀我。
會唔會反而其實一啲可能資深嘅演員？
年紀大啊，或者比較精力、心力異。
誒，即係千祈唔好因為業主代表。
咁其實會唔會預計即係新一屆議會都比較？
經驗方面會唔會有即係擔心或者其他？
新聞台記者及主席係我，咁因為咧即係。
投票工作，每個市民係真係出嚟去誒用好佢嘅投票權咧，噉我哋覺得依個係足夠嘅。
我哋之前全部。
做得會更好。
最近招翻係個。
to vote and choose.
Who could represent them?
company owned by other, you know.
If a candidate has only work experience in one constituency, but joins in different constituency, do you think that is healthy for the future of Malaysia?
I think. And my second question is, for functional constituency candidates, the law requires that they have a substantial connection to that constituency.
Two questions from AFP. So there have been some reports that around 30% of the candidates have connections to mainland Chinese businesses. Do you think that harms the diversity or the competitiveness?
咁所以，我覺得咧就唔係話內耗唔內耗，而係大家可以真真正正為香港誒市民係做好呢個工作咧，我係覺得重要嘅。啊，我亦都講咗好多次啦，啊！
countries as well. So there's no need. I think the important thing is for the candidates to have Hong Kong and Hong Kong people, and also you know as a patriot that love our country, that is good enough. And the other thing is, is up to the voters.
我諗第一樣嘢咧，誒，你要睇到咧，誒，政府啦，誒，我哋立法會啦，商界咧，都用好多方法咧去鼓勵啊，大家出嚟投票。噉我相信依啲誒工作咧係會增加個投票率嘅。噉我最緊要就係做好一個投。
嗱，其實就誒第一樣嘢咧，我答你第二條先啦。其實我哋第七屆立法會，你見到我哋通過一百三十條誒誒依個啊法案啦，啊做咗好多工作嘅。啊，我哋冇內耗，但係我哋係專心去做好我哋嘅立法工作。
長江後浪催前浪，嚇，依個係定律嚟嘅。啊，潮起潮退亦都係定律嚟嘅。雖然我哋有卅幾位議員決定唔同原因咧，係唔再去誒競逐第八屆嘅誒議會，但係我亦都有足夠嘅有經驗嘅議員喺度咧。
會帶領下一屆嘅誒議會。事實上，我第七屆議會我係只係有二十九個議員連任嘅，其餘嗰誒六十個咧都係新丁嚟嘅。啊，我哋都能夠做得咁好，噉我覺得第八屆誒議會用呢個水平嚟講咧，一定做。
I think the second question first is that is up to the presiding the officer, you know, to decide whether that person have you know relevant experience. So it's not for me to say anything. Now Hong Kong is an
open society a diverse society. If you look at it, you know, whoever qualify under our law to be a candidate is good enough. We have you know, in the old days, we have you know, legislator work for you know, other you know.
關。
還在。
多過上一屆。
但係，你少咗八個。
誒對呢個部分嚟講，真係。
嚇？呢個我哋都。
你大聲啲！
覺得選計選競選氣氛係。
點派選委界參選少咗一個人？
我又唔會答得嘅。咁頭先講話，如果有得揀先至係老闆嘅話，會唔會誒支持將來多啲直選嘅議席？
又好噉，依個我諗即係最好嘅就係選舉嘅一個最好嘅效果，就係大家用自己條票去揀。
誒，我諗一個，我哋一定要一步步做啦。噉我哋睇到第八屆議會做得好唔好嘅，咁依個又留待政府中央同埋第八屆議會去。
我諗嗱，最緊要第一樣嘢，我頭先講嘅就話，我覺得今屆嘅候選人咧個質素係好好嘅，嚇。噉你話少一個多半個啊，唔係一件重要事嘅。但係最重要係每個界別都有一揀。
嚟啦，政黨咧、商界咧，都係用唔同嘅方法嚇去呼籲啊！市民去用好佢嘅投票權。噉我相信今屆咧啊，投票率一定係比上一屆啊，係更好嘅。
嗱，第一第一樣嘢咧，誒一涉及議員嘅咧，誒誒誒誒誒選個別人士，我就唔會答嘅。但係我係一定有信心，誒我哋嘅投票率係高過啦。因為事實上你要睇到誒唔同嘅誒人員啊，政府啦，我哋。
係咪？咁最好嘅就係市民有得揀。我哋都講過啦，有得揀就係老闆嘛。咁所以市民選民有得揀，依個就係最好嘅啊！佢一定要用佢張票咧，揀到佢最合適嘅人去代表佢嘅業界又好，代表地區又好。
決定啊，好嘛？O.K. 好，唔該曬。